<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>RimHeroes (D&amp;D Classes) [Alpha]</name>
  <author>Arcanicap</author>
  <packageId>Arcanicap.RimHeroes</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</packageId>
      <displayName>Vanilla Expanded Framework</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2023507013</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>mooloh.dndmenagerie</packageId>
      <displayName>Mooloh's Dnd Menagerie</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2751849453</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
    <li>mooloh.dndmenagerie</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/10035557948060073630/700F63B6E09FE0C84BA28DE9D4716D16D15CEF45/[/img]

[h1]RimHeroes[/h1]
[i]Once in a while, a colonist is born for more.[/i]

Most of your colonists are ordinary people. They farm, they haul, they patch each other up after a raid and carry on. Every so often, though, one of them turns out to be something bigger: a Hero, born with a Dungeons and Dragons class in their bones. A Hero climbs from level 1 to 20, learns real spells, wears armor that grows into legend, gathers a retinue of devoted little companions, and walks into dungeons that would kill anyone else in the colony.

Quick word on why this exists. I wanted to run a proper D&amp;D campaign inside RimWorld, nothing out there quite scratched the itch, so I started building it myself one evening. One class became twelve. A handful of spells became ninety. Then came the dungeons, then the companions, and somewhere in there it grew into the biggest thing I have ever made. RimHeroes is what came out of that. I play it constantly and I am still tuning it, so if something feels off, come tell me and I will take a look.

[hr][/hr]

[h1]A massive thank-you to D&amp;D Menagerie[/h1]
RimHeroes is built on top of [b]Mooloh's D&amp;D Menagerie[/b]. The monsters that fill the dungeons and the beasts your druids turn into all come from their work, and this mod simply would not be here without it. If you get any enjoyment out of RimHeroes, please go give Mooloh a thumbs up and a follow. Half the magic in this pack is theirs.
[b]You need it to play, and you should want it anyway:[/b] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2751849453]Mooloh's D&amp;D Menagerie on the Steam Workshop[/url]

[hr][/hr]

[h1]What you get[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]12 playable D&amp;D classes[/b], each with its own playstyle, signature features, and a suit of class armor that upgrades across five tiers.
[*][b]More than 110 custom spells and abilities[/b] (90 of them spells), hand-built for RimWorld, fire bolt through meteor swarm.
[*][b]Levels 1 to 20[/b] with death saving throws, so a downed Hero rolls to hang on instead of dying on the spot.
[*][b]9 themed dungeons[/b] stuffed with traps, locked reliquaries, and bosses that scale to your colony.
[*][b]A retinue of mim companions[/b] that move in to cook, haul, dig, heal, and fight at your Hero's side.
[*][b]Druid wildshape[/b] into real creatures, up to a full dragon at the height of their power.
[/list]

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/16238378865181349853/71B44D54E93E553889221730EB18D8B4FA9217FC/[/img]

[h1]A hero, not a stat block[/h1]
Every Hero carries a trait and a hidden class engine under the hood. They earn experience from ordinary colony life and from the fights only they can win, and every level makes them tougher. The milestone levels are where they pick up their signature class features.

A Hero who hits zero does not just drop dead. They fall to death's door and start rolling death saving throws. Tend their wounds and you tip the odds in their favor. Leave them bleeding and three failed rolls takes them for good.

Their armor is part of who they are. The [b]class vestment[/b] is bound to the Hero, cannot be stripped off, and grows through five tiers as they level, starting at plain working leathers and ending in legend-forged plate or an archmage's robes. Every class looks different at every tier. You can also fit three [b]vestment inlays[/b] through surgery for extra defense, offense, and utility, in lesser, regular, and greater grades.

[h1]Twelve classes[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]Fighter[/b]: a combat style, second wind, action surge, and the staying power to outlast a brawl.
[*][b]Barbarian[/b]: a rage that pours out damage and shrugs off hits that would drop anyone else.
[*][b]Monk[/b]: unarmored speed, a flurry of blows, and a strike that stuns.
[*][b]Rogue[/b]: a cunning edge, evasion, and a real talent for finding the soft spot.
[*][b]Ranger[/b]: a favored prey, hunter's mark, and a half caster's spell list.
[*][b]Paladin[/b]: an oath worn as armor, lay on hands, and auras that hold the line steady.
[*][b]Cleric[/b]: healing, holy fire, turning the undead, and raising the freshly fallen.
[*][b]Druid[/b]: wildshape into real beasts and the wilds themselves turned on intruders.
[*][b]Wizard[/b]: the full arcane library, fire bolt through meteor swarm.
[*][b]Sorcerer[/b]: raw innate magic with metamagic to bend it.
[*][b]Bard[/b]: songs that wound and songs that mend, plus tricks lifted from every other tradition.
[*][b]Warlock[/b]: pact magic that always answers, a patron's gift, and an eldritch blast that never runs dry.
[/list]
Heroes turn up on their own now and then. You can also make one yourself: hand any colonist a [b]class tome[/b], bought from exotic traders or looted off a fallen enemy Hero, and they wake up as the real thing.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/18074770911893860873/44CACC54EA475DE471ED744B587E096F1911139D/[/img]

[h1]Real spellcasting[/h1]
Eight of the twelve classes cast, and between them they share ninety spells running from cantrips up to ninth level. Magic uses spell slots the old fashioned way. Spend them, run dry, and earn them back by resting. A short rest gives a little back, a long rest gives back everything.
[list]
[*][b]Prepared casters[/b] (Wizard, Cleric, Druid, Paladin) know a wide list and ready a chosen set after a long rest.
[*][b]Known casters[/b] (Sorcerer, Bard, Ranger) lock in a hand-picked list as they level.
[*][b]The Warlock[/b] plays by its own rules: a few strong slots that all come back on a short rest.
[/list]
Set a spell to fire on its own, or hold it and cast it yourself when the moment counts.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/15732677197880314157/233E4560624DE3718124CF28A98C3626F4576896/[/img]

[h1]A retinue of mims[/h1]
Heroes do not work alone. As they level, small devoted creatures called [b]mims[/b] walk into the colony to serve them, each shaped for one job. Some keep the home running as porters, sweepers, diggers, cooks, growers, and doctors. Others go to war: a melee scrapper, a shield-bearing vanguard, a ranged quiller, and a spell-slinging wisp. At level 20 a Hero calls in one extra mim of their choosing.

A mim is bound to its master. Lose one and a replacement shows up within days. Lose the master and the rest scatter in grief. A Hero with their whole retinue around them rests a lot easier.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/14055883178522211658/4C06E011E7ADBA6D0B2F10AF9418BF89228D8A52/[/img]

[h1]Delve the dungeons[/h1]
A growing colony starts drawing attention, and some of that attention is worth raiding back. A dungeon entrance can open right on your map, sit a short march away as a guarded site, or arrive as a quest. Put a party of Heroes together and head down.
[list]
[*][b]9 themed dungeons[/b], each with its own monsters, look, and nasty surprises.
[*][b]Traps you can beat[/b]: catch one with a keen eye, then roll to throw yourself clear.
[*][b]Locked reliquaries[/b] that get harder to crack the longer you work them. Bring a key or a steady hand.
[*][b]Bosses[/b] scaled to your colony's strength, sitting on the best loot.
[*][b]Tiers[/b] that grow with your wealth, a quick delve at the low end and a full capstone trial at the top.
[*][b]Rewards[/b] worth the trip: inlays, experience candy, the rare Heroic Blessing, and a class's legendary capstone weapon.
[/list]
Once a Hero hits the level cap, a hooded stranger comes asking for shelter. Keep him alive past the hunters on his trail and he marks the resting place of your class's ultimate weapon.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/15662071753606976759/73DDD1BE7BF2ECD29668B0D79CD7129EC86C2C95/[/img]

[h1]Wildshape and a fantasy bestiary[/h1]
Your druids take the shapes of real creatures pulled from [b]D&amp;D Menagerie[/b]: a dire wolf, an owlbear, a giant elk, and at full power, a dragon. That same bestiary stocks the dungeons and the wilds with things that belong in a fantasy world. Drop to zero while shifted and you snap back to your own body, hurt but breathing, with no beast carcass left lying around.

[hr][/hr]

[h1]Compatibility[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]Required:[/b] Harmony, Vanilla Expanded Framework, and D&amp;D Menagerie. Menagerie is a hard dependency, since the wildshape forms and a good chunk of the monsters are its creatures.
[*][b]Recommended:[/b] World Tech Level, to keep the world medieval. RimHeroes is built for a low-tech fantasy run and does not lock down the world's tech on its own.
[*][b]Load order:[/b] Harmony, then the DLCs, then Vanilla Expanded Framework, then D&amp;D Menagerie, then RimHeroes.
[*][b]Saves:[/b] safe to drop into a game already in progress. Pulling it back out mid-save is not supported, same as most content mods.
[/list]

[h1]FAQ[/h1]
[b]Where do heroes come from?[/b]
They show up on their own once in a while, or you make one by having a colonist study a class tome.

[b]Are not heroes overpowered?[/b]
Yes, on purpose. A Hero is a rare, story-defining pawn meant to stand against threats that would flatten an ordinary colony. They still bleed, and a careless dungeon run will get them killed.

[b]Is it balanced and finished?[/b]
It is very playable and I am in it daily, but it is still in active development and getting tuned through play. Bug reports and feedback are genuinely welcome.

[b]Can I add it to a save in progress?[/b]
Yes. Removing it later is the part that is not supported.

[h1]Credits[/h1]
[list]
[*]Monsters and wildshape beasts from [b]Mooloh's D&amp;D Menagerie[/b]. Go play it.
[*]Built on [b]Harmony[/b] by Andreas Pardeike.
[*]Built with [b]Vanilla Expanded Framework[/b] by Oskar Potocki and the Vanilla Expanded team.
[*]RimWorld by Ludeon Studios.
[/list]

[i]Dungeons and Dragons is a trademark of Wizards of the Coast. RimHeroes is an unofficial, fan-made tribute and is not affiliated with or endorsed by Wizards of the Coast.[/i]</description>
</ModMetaData>
