<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>RimHeroes (D&amp;D Classes) [Alpha]</name>
  <author>cornhusk39</author>
  <packageId>cornhusk39.RimHeroes</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</packageId>
      <displayName>Vanilla Expanded Framework</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2023507013</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>mooloh.dndmenagerie</packageId>
      <displayName>Mooloh's Dnd Menagerie</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2751849453</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
    <li>mooloh.dndmenagerie</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/16238378865181349853/71B44D54E93E553889221730EB18D8B4FA9217FC/[/img]

[h1]RimHeroes[/h1]
[i]Once in a while, a colonist is born for more.[/i]

Most of your colonists are ordinary people. Every so often, though, one of them turns out to be something bigger: a Hero, born with a Dungeons and Dragons class in their bones. A Hero climbs from level 1 to 20, learns real spells, wears armor that grows into legend, gathers a retinue of devoted little companions, and walks into dungeons that would kill anyone else in the colony.

Quick word on why this exists. I wanted to run a proper D&amp;D campaign inside RimWorld, nothing out there quite scratched the itch, so I started building it myself one evening. One class became twelve. A handful of spells became ninety. Then came the dungeons, then the companions, and it grew into the biggest thing I have ever made. I play it constantly and I am still tuning it, so if something feels off, come tell me.

[hr][/hr]

[h1]A massive thank-you to D&amp;D Menagerie[/h1]
RimHeroes is built on top of [b]Mooloh's D&amp;D Menagerie[/b]. The monsters that fill the dungeons and the beasts your druids turn into all come from their work, and this mod simply would not be here without it. If you enjoy RimHeroes, go give Mooloh a thumbs up and a follow.
[b]You need it to play, and you should want it anyway:[/b] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2751849453]Mooloh's D&amp;D Menagerie on the Steam Workshop[/url]

[hr][/hr]

[h1]What you get[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]12 playable D&amp;D classes[/b], each with its own playstyle, signature features, and a suit of class armor that upgrades across five tiers.
[*][b]More than 110 custom spells and abilities[/b] (90 of them spells), hand-built for RimWorld, fire bolt through meteor swarm.
[*][b]Levels 1 to 20[/b] with death saving throws, so a downed Hero rolls to hang on instead of dying on the spot.
[*][b]9 themed dungeons[/b] stuffed with traps, locked reliquaries, and bosses that scale to your colony.
[*][b]A retinue of mim companions[/b] that move in to cook, haul, dig, heal, and fight at your side.
[*][b]Druid wildshape[/b] into real creatures, up to a full dragon.
[/list]

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/18074770911893860873/44CACC54EA475DE471ED744B587E096F1911139D/[/img]

[h1]Twelve classes[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]Fighter, Barbarian, Monk, Rogue[/b]: combat styles, raging damage, stunning flurries, and a knack for the soft spot.
[*][b]Ranger, Paladin[/b]: a hunter's mark, an oath worn as armor, lay on hands, and auras that hold the line.
[*][b]Cleric, Druid[/b]: healing, holy fire, turning the undead, wildshape, and the wilds turned on intruders.
[*][b]Wizard, Sorcerer, Bard, Warlock[/b]: the full arcane library, innate metamagic, songs, and pact magic.
[/list]
Heroes turn up on their own now and then. You can also make one: hand any colonist a [b]class tome[/b], bought from exotic traders or looted off a fallen enemy Hero, and they wake up as the real thing.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/10035557948060073630/700F63B6E09FE0C84BA28DE9D4716D16D15CEF45/[/img]

[h1]Real spellcasting[/h1]
Eight of the twelve classes cast, sharing ninety spells from cantrips up to ninth level. Magic uses spell slots the old fashioned way: spend them, run dry, and earn them back by resting. Prepared casters ready a set after a long rest, known casters lock in a hand-picked list, and the Warlock leans on pact magic that recharges on a short rest. Set a spell to autocast, or fire it yourself when the moment counts.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/15732677197880314157/233E4560624DE3718124CF28A98C3626F4576896/[/img]

[h1]A retinue of mims[/h1]
Heroes do not work alone. As they level, small devoted creatures called [b]mims[/b] walk into the colony to serve them, each shaped for one job: porters, diggers, cooks, and doctors at home, plus a scrapper, a shield-bearing vanguard, a ranged quiller, and a spell-slinging wisp for the field. A mim is bound to its master. Lose one and a replacement shows up within days. Lose the master and the rest scatter in grief.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/14055883178522211658/4C06E011E7ADBA6D0B2F10AF9418BF89228D8A52/[/img]

[h1]Delve the dungeons[/h1]
A growing colony draws attention, and some of it is worth raiding back. A dungeon entrance can open on your map, sit a short march away as a guarded site, or arrive as a quest.
[list]
[*][b]9 themed dungeons[/b], each with its own monsters, look, and nasty surprises.
[*][b]Traps you can beat[/b]: spot one with a keen eye, then roll to throw yourself clear.
[*][b]Locked reliquaries[/b] that fight back the longer you pick them.
[*][b]Bosses[/b] scaled to your colony, from a quick delve to a full capstone trial.
[*][b]Rewards[/b]: inlays, experience candy, the rare Heroic Blessing, and a class's legendary capstone weapon.
[/list]
Hit the level cap and a hooded stranger comes asking for shelter. Keep him alive past the hunters on his trail and he marks the resting place of your class's ultimate weapon.

[img]https://images.steamusercontent.com/ugc/15662071753606976759/73DDD1BE7BF2ECD29668B0D79CD7129EC86C2C95/[/img]

[h1]Wildshape and a fantasy bestiary[/h1]
Your druids take the shapes of real creatures from [b]D&amp;D Menagerie[/b]: a dire wolf, an owlbear, a giant elk, and at full power, a dragon. That same bestiary stocks the dungeons and the wilds with things that belong in a fantasy world.

[hr][/hr]

[h1]Compatibility[/h1]
[list]
[*][b]Required:[/b] Harmony, Vanilla Expanded Framework, and D&amp;D Menagerie (a hard dependency).
[*][b]Recommended:[/b] World Tech Level, to keep the world medieval.
[*][b]Load order:[/b] Harmony, the DLCs, Vanilla Expanded Framework, D&amp;D Menagerie, then RimHeroes.
[*][b]Saves:[/b] safe to add to a game in progress; removing it mid-save is not supported.
[/list]

[h1]FAQ[/h1]
[b]Where do heroes come from?[/b]
They show up on their own once in a while, or you make one by having a colonist study a class tome.

[b]Is it balanced and finished?[/b]
It is very playable and I am in it daily, but it is still in active development and getting tuned. Bug reports and feedback are genuinely welcome.

[h1]Credits[/h1]
Monsters and wildshape beasts from [b]Mooloh's D&amp;D Menagerie[/b]. Built on [b]Harmony[/b] by Andreas Pardeike and [b]Vanilla Expanded Framework[/b] by Oskar Potocki and team. RimWorld by Ludeon Studios.

[i]Dungeons and Dragons is a trademark of Wizards of the Coast. RimHeroes is an unofficial, fan-made tribute and is not affiliated with or endorsed by Wizards of the Coast.[/i]</description>
</ModMetaData>
